Jack: There are many different coding
languages used in programming, let’s have
a look at some of the more popular ones.
Leah: Python
Python is an interpreted high-level
general-purpose programming language.
It is object oriented and used in
everything from developing application
programming interfaces or API’s,
to being incorporated into machine
learning and data analytics via third
party plug ins like SciPY and Panda.
Python has been used to create
everything from Netflix's recommendation
algorithm to the software that
controls self-driving cars.
Jack: JavaScript
JavaScript often tops the list of the most
popular programming languages due to its
continuous use in open-source projects.
It is a dynamic and interpreted
programming language with
object-oriented capabilities,
that's used for web applications,
game development and lots more.
It allows for creating dynamic
features on web pages that cannot
be done with only HTML and CSS.
Leah: Java
Java is a general purpose, class based,
object-oriented programming language
designed for application development and
has less implementation dependencies.
It is secure, fast, and reliable.
It is widely used for developing
applications in laptops, data centres,
games consoles and mobile phones.
It is essentially the parent of
Java Script and is now mostly
associated with game developers.
It's an open source and a popular
choice for creative coding.
Jack: C++
C++ is a general-purpose programming
language based on the older language C.
It is used in one way or another in every
complex system in the world from Operating
Systems to Government mainframes.
Even Google uses this
programming language for its most
resource intensive operations.
Internet of Things [IoT] devices also
make use of C++, and it is useful for
building complex open-source systems.
Leah: C#
C# is another object-oriented language
commonly used in game developing.
A member of the 'C' language family
it shares similar logic to C++
but is regarded as easier to use.
It is commonly used for Windows
applications, and it’s recommended for
building games on the ‘Unity’ engine.
The language’s specific syntax makes
it easy for 3D development, so is
good for making VR applications.
Jack: SQL
SQL stands for Structured
Query Language and is used to
communicate with a database.
For those who wish to work with databases
SQL is ideal as it is a very practical
language and easy to use and uses a
syntax that is similar to English which
helps to create a smooth learning curve.
Leah: Scala
Scala is another popular
programming language often
seen as an alternative to Java.
It is a multi- paradigm general purpose
programme, supporting both object oriented
and functional programming and can be
applied to many areas of development.
Jack: Ruby
Ruby is regarded as simple
to learn and a good starting
place for budding developers.
It is most often used to build
websites and web applications.
Leah: Swift
Swift is a relatively new language
that has a strong following due
to the convenience it offers
to open-source developers.
It is behind most modern iOS applications.
Jack: PHP
PHP is a programming language
mostly used for web development.
It is a simple language with logic and
syntax that can be mastered quite quickly.
It is used for WordPress websites
and platforms like Facebook.